A Guide to the Papers of J. Rives Childs
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
The Papers of J. Rives Childs
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9256-d
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The papers were packed at Mr. Childs' home in Nice and shipped to the University in January, 1972.
Scope and Content Information
The additional papers of J. Rives Childs accessioned as #9256-d comprise 19 Hollinger boxes and 1 oversize folio. In addition to his manuscripts, there are nine books and magazines and a newspaper.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into three parts, the first of which contains correspondence and personal items. Childs' correspondence is mainly with his family and the Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel. Other correspondence is grouped under the heading General Correspondence. Among Childs' personal items are articles written by him, Confederate bills, a diary of Mrs. John W. Childs, 1873- 1876, items concerning Childs' student days, and pictures of Childs and his wife.
The second part of the collection contains papers relating to the life of Jacques Casanova. Included are copies of Casanova's Memoirs and letters, articles written about Casanova, research notes of Childs and other Casanova scholars, and correspondence between Childs and various people interested in Casanova. Two boxes contain microfilmed copies of Casanova materials.
The last part of this collection contains two manuscripts about the middle east and three boxes of snapshots of Childs' foreign travels.
Printed Materials Belonging to J. Rives Chiles
American Artist, v. 23, no. 3, issu 223, 1959 March, 72 pp. The American Foreign Service, supplement to The American Foreign Service Journal, v.XIII, no. 11, 1936 November, 172 pp. The American Foreign Service, supplement to the "Photographic Register of November, 1936," The American Foreign Service Journal, v.18, no.4, 1949 April, 44 pp. Ballyhoo, v. 2, nos. 2-5, 1932 February-June The Bomb, v.XXV, clas of 1909, Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, Virginia The Bomb, v.XXVI, class of 1910, Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, Virginia "The Chester Beatty Library, Dublin," Emery Walker Limited, MCMLVIII, 36 pp., w/inscription, "To Rives Childs from A. Chester Beatty, April 1959" Childs, J. Rives, Giacomo Casanova De Seingalt in Selbstzeugnissen und Bilddokumnten, Rowohlt, 1960, 178 pp. Lectures Pour Tous Constellation, no.207, 1971 April, 182 pp. Lynchburg Republican, v.XL, no. 35, 1873 July 4
Contents List
- Correspondence and Personal Items of J. Rives Childs
  - J. Rives Childs to his mother and father 1900-1904, 10 ALS; 25pp., 5 env. (Box 1)
    w/enclosed ALS, J. Wesley Childs to his father (not in his hand), and enclosed ALS, Mary Childs to Aunt Lucy
  - J. Rives Childs to his grandmother, mother, and father 1905-1910, 15 ALS, 6 APCS; 31pp., 12 env. (Box 1)
  - J. Wesley Childs (brother of Childs) to his mother and father 1901-1906, 13 ALS; 24pp., 10 env. (Box 1)
    and AMsS My Life by J. Wesley Childs, 2pp.
  - Harlan B. Clark (Dept. of State) to Childs 1950 July 10, TLS; 2pp. (Box 1)
  - William M. Franklin (Dept. of State) to Childs 1963 May 14, TLS; 2pp. (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence 1966-1967, 26pp. (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence 1968, 53 items (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence 1969 Jan-Apr, 44 items (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence 1969 May-Dec, ca. 100 items (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence 1970, ca. 90 items (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence 1970, ca. 100 items (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence 1971, ca. 40 items (Box 2)
  - General Correspondence 1971, ca. 80 items (Box 2)
  - Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs 1966 Oct-Dec, 15 ALS (Box 2)
  - Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs 1967 Jan-Jul, 42 ALS (Box 2)
  - Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs 1967 Aug-Dec, 41 ALS (Box 2)
  - Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs 1968 Feb-July, 45 ALS, 1 APCS (Box 2)
  - Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs 1968 Aug-Dec, 43 ALS (Box 3)
  - Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs 1969 Jan-July, 47 ALS (Box 3)
  - Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs 1969 Aug-Dec, 26 ALS (Box 3)
  - Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs 1970 Jan-Aug, 30 ALS (Box 3)
  - Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs 1970 Sep-Dec, 20 ALS, 2 telegrams (Box 3)
  - Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs 1971 Jan-May, 17 ALS (Box 3)
  - Items kept w/letters from Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel 1967-1971, 7 items (Box 3)
    including 2 TLS, Childs to the Baroness
  - Copies of portions of letters from Baroness Marcelle de Jouvenel to Childs, in French 1966-1971, TMs, 22pp. (Box 3)
  - The Arab-Jewish Problem in Retrospect, an extract from Farewell to Foreign Service: Thirty Years in the Near East by Childs 1969, TMs, 17 pp. (Box 4)
  - A Brief History of the American Church, Nice (1873-1970), by Childs and a church program 1969, n.d., TMs, 17 pp. (Box 4)
  - "The Buddha of Kamakura," by Childs, w/autograph revisions n.d., AMsS, 2 pp. (Box 4)
  - The Book Exchange, v. 97, 1956 April, and v. 98, 1956 May, both w/large advertisements for Casanoviana by Childs 1956 Apr-May (Box 4)
  - Printed letter to the editors of The New York Review re: Casanova, by Childs 1967 April 6, 2 pp. (Box 4)
  - Xerox copy of Foreign Relations of the United States: Diplomatic Papers, 1944 v. V, includig letters of Childs 1965, 15 pp. (Box 4)
  - Giacoma Casanova de Seingalt by Childs 1960, TMs, ca. 160 pp. (Box 4)
  - Up From Earth's Center by Childs, foreward and chapters I-VII, 147 pp. n.d., TMs, 147 pp. (Box 4)
  - Up From Earth's Center by Childs, chapters VIII-XVI n.d., TMs, 166 pp. (Box 4)
  - Childs to Lawrence Grow re: Childs's ms., Whirligig of Time, w/included TMs of criticisms of the ms. 1963, TL copy, 4 pp. (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous TMs and AMs drafts by Childs 1968, n.d., 29 pp. (Box 4)
  - 125 Confederate bills, mostly from Virginia, 2 printed sheets of bills, 1 Confederate flag sicker, and 1 paroled prisoner pass belonging to J.W. Childs 1862-1865 (Box 5)
  - Diary with the names of Mrs. John W. Childs and Miss Lucy Brown written on the front page, and picture of a man inserted in the back pocket 1873-1876 (Box 5)
  - Snapshots and photographs of Childs, his relatives, and his friends ca. 1893-1950, 55 items (Box 5)
  - Teaching certificate of Childs from Randolph-Macon College 1912 Sep 13 (Box 5)
  - 17 negatives of scenes and activities at Randolph-Macon College 1912 (Box 5)
  - 19 snapshots and 2 negatives labelled Harvard, 1914-1915 1914-1915 (Box 5)
  - Military papers from WWI concerning Childs 1917, 4 pp. (Box 5)
  - Printed articles about Nikolai Fechin, painter of Childs and Georgina de Brylkine Childs portraits 1924, 1942 (Box 5)
  - 2 glass negatives of portraits of Childs and Mrs. Childs, painted by Nikolai Fechin n.d. (Box 5)
  - 6 pictures of Childs 1926, 1941-1945, ca. 1949, n.d (Box 5)
  - Printed announcement and menu of a testimonial dinner honoring Mr. and Mrs. Childs in Tangier, w/signatures of attendants 1945 June 15 (Box 5)
  - 2 press releases about Childs 1949 or 1950, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Printed items re: Childs's relationships with Randolph-Macon College, and Luther W. White, III to Childs 1955-1969, TLS, 75 pp. (Box 5)
  - 2 travel itineraries prepared for Mr. and Mrs. Childs 1960, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Printed article, The Alumni from V.M.I. Review, mentioning Childs 1962, 4 pp. (Box 5)
  - Booklet, Old and Rare Books, mentioning Childs n.d., 96 pp. (Box 5)
  - 4 miscellaneous menus, 2 w/signatures 1868-1969 (Box 5)
  - 21 negatives of Childs, his family, and his days at V.M.I. 1908-1910 (Box 5)
- Papers Relating to the Life and Works of Jaques Casanova
  - Memoirs of Jaques Casanova, v. 9, chapters I-V n.d., TMs, ca. 150 pp. (Box 6)
    These items represent an attempt by Childs to marry Lafourque, Schutz and Busoni texts of Casanova's Memoirs with particular reference to the variants.
  - Memoirs of Jaques Casanova, v.9, chapters VI-XI n.d., TMs, ca. 150 pp. (Box 6)
  - Memoirs of Jaques Casanova, v.9, part II, chapters VIII-XII n.d., TMs, ca. 150 pp. (Box 6)
  - Memoirs of Jaques Casanova, v. 10, part I n.d., TMs, ca. 175 pp. (Box 6)
  - Memoirs of Jaques Casanova, v.10, part II n.d., TMs, ca. 150 pp. (Box 6)
  - Memoirs of Jaques Casanova, v.11, part I n.d., TMs, ca. 150 pp. (Box 7)
  - Memoirs of Jaques Casanova, v.11, part II n.d., TMs, ca. 150 pp. (Box 7)
  - Memoirs of Jaques Casanova, v.12, part I n.d., TMs, ca. 150 pp. (Box 7)
  - Memoirs of Jaques Casanova, beginning of v. 13 1960, TMs, 68 pp. (Box 7)
  - plays, La Lorgnette Menteuse and Le Polemoscope, written by J. Casanova, mechanically reproduced (in French) ca. 1956, AMs, 5 pp. (Box 7)
  - Essai D'Egoisme(2 copies), Les Voeux de Chasteté, Mort de Reobespierre, and Sur La Langue Françaisen.d., AMs, TMs, ca. 40 items (Box 7)
    all in French and kept in originial order in an envelope labelled Veze Archive-Essays and Notes of C[asanova] (copies),
  - Letters used by Gugitz in his book, Giacomo Casanova und sein Leben and AMs notes n.d., 54 pp. (Box 7)
  - copies of Casanova correspondence, 1769-1796 n.d., ALS and TL, ca. 50 items (Box 7)
    in an envelope labelled Veze Archive
  - Notes and xeroxes of Casanova letters archived near Prague n.d., TMs, ca. 150 pp. (Box 8)
  - Xeroxes of Casanova letter archived near Prague n.d., ca. 150 pp. (Box 8)
  - Xeroxes of Casanova letters archived near Prague n.d., ca. 100 pp. (Box 8)
  - Copies of microfilmed letters to Casanova, 1757-1798, in French 1960, n.d., TMs, ca. 100 pp. (Box 8)
    including ALS La Direttrice, Biblioteca Nazionale di S. Marco to Childs, from Casanova Archives in Prague
  - Negative photostats of letters from Jean Baptist Boyer de Fonscolombe and from Joseph Roch Boyer de Fonscolombe, 1762-1779 n.d., 10 pp. (Box 8)
  - Tage Bull to E. Maynial 1908-1818, 20 ALS, 2 APCS (Box 8)
    w 1 APCS, Louis Bobé to E. Maynial (both in French), w/ 2 related TMs (in German)
  - Dr. Guède to E. Maynila (in French) ca. 1908-1919, 43 ALS, 1 APCS, ca. 50 items (Box 8)
  - Notes of Dr. Guède, a student of Casanova (in French) n.d., ca. 25 items (Box 8)
  - Fr. Kohn to E. Maynial (in French) 1911-1913, 1 ALS, 3 APCS (Box 8)
  - Horace Bleackley to E. Maynial, w/related notes (in French) 1911-1916, 9 ALS, 1 APCS (Box 8)
  - Aldo Rava to E. Maynial (in French) 1911-1920, 32 ALS, 23 APCS (Box 8)
  - J. Verset to E. Maynial, w/5 related items (in French) 1913-1916 (Box 8)
  - Luis Ulbra (?) to René Veze, pamphlet entitled Christophe Colomb,(in French) and an unidentified book cover. 1929, n.d., 3 ALS (Box 9)
    All in a folder labelled Postface-La Publication des Memoires
  - Biblioteca Nazionale Centrale to Signore, 2 book advertisements, 1 book cover, 2 pictures and AMs note all re: Giacomo Casanova (in Italian) 1932, ALS (Box 9)
  - Falchetta to Childs, and notes about Henriette, or Jeanne-Marie Boyer de Fonscolombe, née d' Alber, and her marriage and family 1960, n.d., 4 ALS, 2 TMs, 18 pp. (Box 9)
  - notes and photocopies of book title pages all re: J. Casanova, sent to Childs by F.A. Brockhaus (in German and French) 1960, n.d., 1 ALS, 2 TMs, AMs notes, 13 items (Box 9)
  - Walker (The University Press of Virginia) to Childs, copies of Casanova letters (in French), TMs Drucker, Verleger, und der Autor Cassanova in der 'Histoire de ma Vie'(in German), TMs re: Gyula Rudnyanszky and TMs bibliography (in Hungarian) 1969, n.d., TLS, TMs, ca. 28 pp. (Box 9)
    all in an unlabelled folder
  - untitled, I-V n.d., TMs, ca. 150 pp. (Box 9)
    all in a folder labelled Notes prepared by Ch. Samaran and J. Rives Childs for a critical edition of Casanova's 'Historoire de ma Vie', v. I-V, inclusive of the Brockhaus ed. 1960,(in French). These notes were prepared by M. Charles Samaran for a critical edition of Casanova's Histoire de ma Vie in 12 vols. for Garnier Freres, but were never used.
  - Notes for Casanova's Histoire de ma Vie, tome I. n.d., TMs, ca. 60 pp. (Box 9)
    These notes were prepared by M. Charles Samaran for a critical edition of Casanova's Histoire de ma Vie in 12 vols. for Garnier Freres, but were never used.
  - A Great Adventurer and His Times: A Biography of Casanova Based on New Documents, Introduction and chapters I-VIII n.d., TMs (Box 9)
  - A Great Adventurer and His Times: A Biography of Casanova Based on New Documents, chapters IX-end n.d., TMs (Box 9)
  - 2 TMs about Elizabeth Chudleigh, w/related notes, letters, and pictures 1908, n.d., 2 TMs, ca. 30 items (Box 9)
  - Materials and correspondence of Brockhaus and Veze 1908-1939, ca. 100 items (Box 10)
    re: the works of Casanova, including a newspaper entitled Le Petit Bastiais, 1922 Sep 10, all in French and kep in original order in a folder marked Casanova Correspondence
  - Review by E. Le Gallo and printed review of Casanova et son Temps by E. Maynial (in French) ca. 1910, AMsS, 7 pp. (Box 10)
  - Une Amitié de Casanova: Le Comte Maximillien Lamberg by Edouard Maynial, w/related letter 1922, n.d., AmsS, 32 pp. (Box 10)
  - Inventory of Casanova papers compiled by Beinhard Marr 1957, ca. 175 pp. (Box 10)
  - Inventory of Casanova Papers n.d., 21 pp. (Box 10)
  - Les Trois Passages de Casanova sur la [acute]Côte de' Azur, 2 copies, w/related TLS (in French) 1959, TMsS, 50 pp. (Box 10)
  - re: the life and works of Justinienne Wynne (in French) by Francis L. Mars and by Baron Ernouf 1960, n.d., 2 TMs, 23 pp. (Box 10)
  - Printed article signed, Aragon et Maurois by Radu Floresco (in French) 1960 March, 9 pp. (Box 10)
  - Printed advertisement for subscription to The Memoirs of Casanova in Facsimile, edited by F.A. Brockhaus (partly in French) 1960 Dec, 8 pp. (Box 10)
  - Les Véritables Mémoires de Casanova, by Ch. Samara (in French) 1964, TMs, 26 pp. (Box 10)
  - Xerox, Mémoires de J. Casanova de Seingalt ecrits par Lui-Même1966, TMs, 38 pp. (Box 10)
  - Xerox of printed article, Proposta per una Revisione Storiogragica: Giocomo Casanova, by Giampiero Bozzolato (in Italian) 1967, 9 pp. (Box 10)
  - Casanova à Nice et à Menton by Dr. F. Mars, 3 copies, 1 w/autograph revisions and attached AMs note n.d., TMs, 20 pp. (Box 10)
  - Appendixes drafted for a projected edition of Casanova's Memoirs to record the variant texts n.d., TMs. 116 pp. (Box 10)
  - Copy of Acrostics, Anagrams, and Chaucer by William F. Friedman and Elizabeth S. Friedman 1959 Jan, 20 pp. (Box 10)
  - "Livres Anciens et Modernes" by Jean Rousseau-Girard n.d., booklet, 38 pp. (Box 10)
  - Notes labelled B-P VI(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 200 pp. (Box 11)
  - Notes labelled B-P VI(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 200 pp. (Box 11)
  - Notes Labelled BP-VII(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 200 pp. (Box 11)
  - Notes Labelled BP-VII(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 100 pp. (Box 11)
  - Notes Labelled BP-VIII(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 200 pp. (Box 11)
  - Notes labelled IX(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 200 pp. (Box 12)
  - Notes labelled IX(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 80 pp. (Box 12)
  - Notes labelled Vol. X(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 200 pp. (Box 12)
  - Notes labelled Vol. X(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 200 pp. (Box 12)
  - Notes labelled Vol. XI(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 200 pp. (Box 12)
  - Notes labelled Vol. XI(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 100 pp. (Box 13)
  - Notes labelled Vol. XII(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 200 pp. (Box 13)
  - Notes labelled Vol. XII(in French) n.d., TMs, ca. 80 pp. (Box 13)
  - Lists of subscribers to Casanova Gleanings 1959-1960, 5 TLS, 4 lists, 15 pp. (Box 13)
  - Casanova Correspondence 1968, 79 items (Box 13)
  - Casanova Correspondence 1969, 71 items (Box 13)
  - Casanova Correspondence 1970, 72 items (Box 13)
  - Casanova Correspondence 1971 (Box 42 items)
  - Manuscripts and printed works by Casanova from the Czech Archives in Prague, ca. 50 manuscripts, ca. 20 printed works (Box 14-15)
  - Printed items re: the Eighteenth Century from the Bibliothéque Nationale in Paris, ca. 20 items (Box 14-15)
  - Pictures of Casanova and his associates, ca. 50 items (Box 14-15)
  - Manuscripts chiefly by Casanova, letters, some from, but chiefly to, Casanova from unidentified sources (possibly the Czech Archives), ca. 100 manuscripts, ca. 600 letters (Box 14-15)
  - Illustration and 22 microfilm cuts used in Rowohlt's German translation of Casanova by Childs ca. 1970 (Box 16)
  - Collection of 9 pictures of Jaques Casanova 1968, n.d. (Box 16)
  - 68 illustrations for Raoul Veze's edition of Mémoires de Casanova, I n.d. (Box 16)
  - 72 illustrations for Raoul Veze's edition of Mémoires de Casanova, II n.d. (Box 16)
  - 10 illustrations of people and places in a folder labelled, Angleterren.d. (Box 16)
  - 27 illustrations in a folder labelled Etranger-Allemagne, Autriche, Russie, Suissen.d. (Box 16)
  - 10 illustrations in a folder labelled Iconographie de Casanovan.d. (Box 16)
  - ca. 125 illustrations w/related notes in a folder labelled Illustrations documentaries pour Casanovaca. 1927 (Box 16)
  - 39 illustrations of Casanova materials collected by Childs n.d. (Box 16)
  - ca. 125 illustrations for La Fin d'un Adventurier: Casanova aprés les Mémoiresn.d. (Box 16)
  - 2 glass negatives of portraits of women, kept in a box labelled, Henrietten.d. (Box 16)
  - 1 glass negative of a portrait of a woman, and 19 photographs of Childs's visit to Taizz w/ accompanying description, all kept in a box labelled, "Elizabeth Chudleigh" n.d. (Box 16)
  - 2 pictures, possibly of the courtesan, Louise O'Murphy, w/printed descriptions n.d., 2 pp. (Box 16)
- Papers Relating to and Photographs of J. Rives Childs' Foreign Travels
  - What Mohammed Said and What He Meant, a book review by Anne Fremantle of The Eternal Message of Muhammed, by 'Abd-al-Rahman 'Azzam 1964 March 15, Printed article, 1 p. (Box 17)
  - 3 TMs about Moslem families sent to Childs by Shenfè Druhan (one in French) n.d., 21 pp. (Box 17)
  - Large map of Addis Abada 1952 August (Box 17)
  - 2 photographs and 40 negatives labelled American Ambulance, France, 19151915 (Box 17)
  - 3 photographs and 49 negatives labelled Photos taken in Paris, Juilly, while with American Ambulance Corps in France in 19151915
  - 38 photographs taken during WWI ca. 1917-1918 (Box 17)
  - 47 photographs labelled A[merican] R[elief] A[dministration]...in Russiaca. 1921-1923 and n.d. (Box 17)
  - 7 photographs and 7 negatives labelled Egypt 1930s (Box 17)
  - 17 photographs and 20 negatives labelled Egyptn.d. (Box 17)
  - 1 picture postcard and 4 negatives of Egypt n.d. (Box 17)
  - 54 photographs and 1 negative labelled Cairo and Pageant of Persian.d. (Box 17)
  - 17 photographs labelled Iran in 1934 or 351934 or 1935 (Box 17)
  - 51 negatives labelled Persia, 1934-1935 1934-1935 (Box 17)
  - 16 photographs and 1 negative labelled Persia 1934-1935 1934-1935 (Box 17)
  - 35 photographs labelled Persian.d. (Box 17)
  - 31 photographs labelled Persian.d. (Box 17)
  - 4 photographs labelled Persia, American Legationn.d. (Box 17)
  - 60 photographs labelled Cairo to Teheran prints and other excursions in Persian.d. (Box 17)
  - 13 photographs and 16 negatives labelled Nice to Athens, 19361936 (Box 17)
  - 10 photographs labelled Greece to Athens1936 (Box 17)
  - 8 photographs and 8 negatives labelled Transjordan, 1936?1936 (Box 17)
  - 6 photographs and 6 negatives labelled Spain and France, 19361936 (Box 17)
  - 13 photographs and 12 negatives labelled France and Spanish border at and around Iran, 19361936 (Box 17)
  - 20 photographs and 21 negatives labelled France, 1936 1936 (Box 17)
  - 16 photographs of the French Alps n.d. (Box 17)
  - 14 negatives labelled Spain and Bermudan.d. (Box 18)
  - 61 negatives labelled Spain and Portugal n.d. (Box 18)
  - 16 photographs of people and places in Morocco 1941 (Box 18)
  - 1 photograph and 37 negatives labelled Morocco, 1941-45 1941-1945 (Box 18)
  - 14 photographs labelled Tangier 1941-1942 (Box 18)
  - 10 negatives labelled Tangiern.d. (Box 18)
  - 33 photographs labelled Tangiern.d. (Box 18)
  - 20 photographs labelled Rabat and Sale, Meknes, Fex 1941-1943 (Box 18)
  - 45 photographs labelled Pictures of various places in Arabia Peninsula, Saudi Arabis, Yenan 1942-1952 (Box 18)
  - 11 photographs labelled Spain, 19431943 (Box 18)
  - 19 negatives labelled Portugal, 19431943 (Box 18)
  - 55 negatives labelled Spain and Portugaln.d. (Box 18)
  - 8 photographs labelled Patton-Orgaz meeting1943 (Box 18)
  - 9 negatives labelled Patton-Orgaz meeting1943 (Box 18)
  - 11 photographs labelled Patton-Orgaz meetings1943 (Box 18)
  - 21 negatives labelled Clark-Orgaz meeting A[merican] R[elief] A[dministration], 19431943 (Box 18)
  - 46 negatives labelled Clark-Orgaz meeting, June 19431943 (Box 18)
  - 68 photographs and 2 negatives labelled Photos of U.S. Navy- Morocco1943 or 1944 (Box 18)
  - 20 photographs labelled Scenes of Tetjan1944 (Box 19)
  - 108 photographs labelled Yemen, 19461946 (Box 19)
  - 12 photographs labelled Yemen1947 (Box 19)
  - 59 photographs labelled Yemenn.d. (Box 19)
  - 43 photographs labelled Saudi Arabiaca. 1947 (Box 19)
  - 19 photographs labelled Saudi Arabian.d. (Box 19)
  - 5 photographs and 8 negatives labelled Ethiopia, 1951-1953 1951-1953 (Box 19)
  - 46 photographs and 45 negatives labelled Ethiopia, 19521952 (Box 19)
  - Jaques Marsanto Childs w/6 photographs of S. Maria d' Angeli a Murano1967 Nov, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 19)
  - 6 photographs and 12 negatives labelled Jiddan.d. (Box 19)
  - 16 negatives labelled Nelillan.d. (Box 19)
  - 16 photographs labelled Marrakeshn.d. (Box 19)
  - 21 photographs labelled Mazagan, Safi, Mogadar, Tiznit, Taroudant, to Marrakeshn.d. (Box 19)
  - 10 photographs labelled Ouarzazate, Zagora, Tamgroutn.d. (Box 19)
  - Large picture of King Abdul Aziz Ibn Saud n.d. (Box 19)
  - 16 photographs and 16 negatives of miscellaneous places n.d. (Box 19)
  - Map of Washington, D.C. n.d. (Box 19)
- Oversize Items
  - 18th century engraving of a city, labelled Vue de la Ville et du Port de Palermen.d.
  - 2 18th century steel engravings of scenes of a homelife n.d.